ISRAEL ALAGBE

Full-Stack Software Developer

Personal Information

israelalagbe53@gmail.com

+2348107760824



https://github.com/israelalagbe



18A, Olu-Arisegbede Street, Palmgrove, Lagos, Nigeria

PROFILE

An experienced Full-Stack developer with 4+ years of software development experience, who has worked extensively on both the front-end and back-end aspect of web applications using Angular, React, Laravel, and Node. Also knowledgeable in unit testing, continuous integration/continuous deployment(CI/CD) and cloud hosting.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Finance Life Technologies Limited (Riby) | Yaba, Lagos, Nigeria.

Frontend Developer

https://riby.me/ (L) July 2019 - Present

Riby is a Digital Banking & Financial Services Platform for Cooperatives, Trade/Business Groups & Salary Earners in Company Groups.

Tools/Tech Used: Angular, React, JavaScript/TypeScript, Redux.

- Worked on Riby Agent landing page.
- ii. Worked on Riby Agent Network Control Center(ANCC) for managing agent's operations
- iii. Maintained other landing pages across other Riby products.
- iv. Worked on Riby Pay dashboard.
- v. Assigned tasks to interns, and managed their projects.
- vi. Worked on Riby Single Sign On (SSO) page used for authentication across all Riby products.

Skooleeo Technology | Surulere, Lagos, Nigeria.

Fullstack Developer

https://skooleeo.com/ (L) April 2019 - July 2019

Skooleeo is a software as a service(SaaS) management app for schools to connect teachers, parents and students. With Skooleeo, teachers can manage classrooms better and students are able to optimize learning with parent's engagement.

Tools/Tech Used: Laravel, Mysql, JavaScript, AWS

- i. Designed the whole software architecture and data structure for the back-end.
- ii. Worked on the landing page
- iii. Developed a role-based teacher, parent, school, and admin dashboard.
- iv. Optimized the back-end so it can scale for thousands of concurrent users.

Symple Innovations | Ikeja, Lagos, Nigeria.

Full-Stack Developer

https://symple.tech/
January 2019 - April 2019

Symple Innovations delivers simple, swift solutions that ease your everyday life. Symple Innovation's sole purpose is to bring this to reality and make ease, a norm.

Tools/Tech Used: Laravel, Mysgl, JavaScript, Heroku

- i. Worked on moov app backend.
- ii. Worked on admin pages for managing users, drivers and rides on the moov app.
- iii. Refactored the legacy code base to make it more readable and easier to add new features.

Megalf Global Network | Ibadan, Oyo state, Nigeria.

Full-Stack Developer

Megalf Global Network is an organization that specializes in the creation and provision of integrated information and communication technology (ICT) solutions to support, drive and sustain the administrative functions of an organization.

Tools/Tech Used: Angular/AngularJs, Laravel, Ionic, Mysql, ¡Query, Firebase

- i. Worked UDR radio admin page for managing music, artists and genres on UDR radio app
- ii. Worked on AjuwayaTales web app, a social network for coppers to share information.
- iii. Built a hospital card template generator web app for Ibadan centre hospital, to digitize their hospital card generation process
- iv. Built an academic progress monitoring website for Christian and Medical Dental Association
- v. Built back-end for Boomtips, a football bet prediction app.
- vi. Built a manuscript submission website for publishing journals.

Tech Instant | Ibadan, Oyo state, Nigeria.

Freelance Web Developer

(L) 2016 - 2018

Tools/Tech Used: AngularJs, React, Laravel, Ionic, Mysgl.

- i. Facilitated students on web development.
- ii. Built a hybrid mobile application for checking symptoms of illnesses.
- iii. Built a school mobile handbook hybrid app for students of Federal College of animal health.
- iv. Built a biology note hybrid app which includes animations to simplify learning biology for students.
- v. Built a Siwes/IT placement websites for students looking for Siwes/IT placement.
- vi. Built a Library management website for Federal college of animal health.

vii. Built an Appstore web application for downloading Android applications.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript/TypeScript, PHP

Technologies: Angular, React/Redux, Laravel, Node/Express, Git, HTML/CSS

Databases: MySql, MongoDB, Firebase.

EDUCATION

Federal College of Animal Health and Production Technology National Diploma In Computer Science 2015 - 2017

ABILITIES

- i. Ability to work under pressure and independently.
- ii. Willingness to invest long hours into exploring problems and seeing their solutions through to completion.
- iii. Ability to write clean, easily readable and testable code.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS DevOps CI/CD

AWS DevOps Continuous Integration and Delivery CI/CD for NodeJS using AWS CodePipeline, AWS Elastic Beanstalk and Mocha - **Udemy**

JavaScript and Node Applications Testing

Unit Testing, Feature/integration testing, Mocking, Spying & stubbing, Asynchronous tests, Database testing, End to end testing - **Udemy**